Guide to the Joseph Barnes Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Joseph Barnes Papers,
1923-1970
Barnes, Joseph, 1907-1970.
18.5 linear ft. (ca.18,000 items in 40 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079827
History
Journalist, editor, author, and educator. Barnes was editor and foreign correspondent for the New York Herald Tribune, 1931-1948, with the Office of War Information, 1941-1944, editor of the New York Star, 1948-1949, and a book editor at Simon and Schuster, Publishers, 1951-1970. He also translated several books by Russian and Franch authors.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, dispatches, documents, clippings and other printed materials concerning his career as an editor and correspondent for the New York Herald Tribune in Moscow, Berlin and New York, as a staff member of the Institute of Pacific Relations from 1932 to 1934, as deputy director in the Office of War Information overseas branch, 1941-44, as an owner and editor of the New York Star, 1948-49, as an instructor in communications at Sarah Lawrence College, 1950-1951, as a book editor at Simon and Schuster, Publishers, 1951-1970, and as an author and translator.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged. Box 1-5: Cataloged correspondence & manuscripts; Box 6-18: Uncataloged papers, 1923-1954; box 19-40: Uncataloged papers-Simon and Schuster, Inc., A-Z.
Subjects
United States.--Congress.--House.--Committee on Un-American Activities.; United States.--Office of War Information.--Overseas Operations Branch.; American Newspaper Guild.; British Broadcasting Corporation.; Communist Party of the United States of America.; Council on Foreign Relations.; Institute of Pacific Relations.; Sarah Lawrence College.; Simon and Schuster, inc.; Time, inc.; Harvard Tercentenary Conference of Arts and Sciences (1936 :--Cambridge, Mass.); Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.; Alsop, Joseph, 1910-1989.; Arendt, Hannah, 1906-1975.; Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1893-1973.; Aydelotte, Frank, 1880-1956.; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.; Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981.; Barr, Stringfellow, 1897-1982.; Beard, Charles Austin, 1874-1948.; Beebe, Lucius Morris, 1902-1966.; Benton, William, 1900-1973.; Berle, A. A. (Adolf Augustus), 1866-1960.; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977.; Bohlen, Charles E. (Charles Eustis), 1904-1974.; Bowers, Claude Gernade, 1879-1958.; Bowles, Chester, 1901-1986.; Brandt, Willy, 1913-1992.; Brown, John Mason, 1900-1969.; Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1891-1967.; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974.; Catledge, Turner, 1901-1983.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971.; Zhou, Enlai, 1898-1976.; Churchill, Randolph S. (Randolph Spencer), 1911-1968.; Cockburn, Claud, 1904-1981.; Commager, Henry Steele, 1902-1998.; Comstock, Ada Louise.; Cooper, Diana, 1892-1986.; Corwin, Norman, 1910-; Cowan, Louis G., 1909-1976.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Crichton, Kyle, 1896-1960.; Crossman, R. H. S. (Richard Howard Stafford), 1907-1974.; Curti, Merle Eugene, 1897-; Davenport, Marcia, 1903-1996.; Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952.; Davies, Joseph Edward.; Dayan, Moshe, 1915-1981.; De Voto, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955.; Donovan, William J. (William Joseph), 1883-1959.; Doolittle, James Harold, 1896-1993.; Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-1980.; Driberg, Tom, 1905-1976.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Duranty, Walter, 1884-1957.; Edel, Leon, 1907-1997.; Edman, Irwin, 1896-1954.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985.; Ernst, Morris Leopold, 1888-1976.; Evans, Ernestine, 1889-1967.; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-1999.; Farago, Ladislas.; Fels, Joseph, 1854-1914.; Field, Marshall, 1893-1956.; Flexner, Abraham, 1866-1959.; Fortas, Abe.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Fromm, Erich, 1900-1980.; Fry, Varian, 1907-1967.; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995.; Galantière, Lewis, 1895-1977.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Gannett, Lewis, 1891-1966.; Gary, Romain.; Gellhorn, Martha, 1908-1998.; Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938.; Greenslet, Ferris, 1875-1959.; Gruenther, Alfred M., 1899-; Guérard, Albert Léon, 1880-1959.; Gunther, John, 1901-1970.; Halsman, Philippe.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986.; Haydn, Hiram Collins, 1907-1973.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Hersey, John, 1914-1993.; Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966.; Hindus, Maurice Gerschon, 1891-1969.; Horne, Lena.; Houseman, John.; Howe, Quincy, 1900-1977.; Huebsch, B. W. (Benjamin W.), 1876-1964.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Ingersoll, Ralph, 1900-1985.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1874-1971.; Johnson, Nunnally.; Josephson, Matthew, 1899-1978.; Kellogg, Paul Underwood, 1879-1958.; Kempton, Murray, 1918-; Kennan, George F. (George Frost), 1904-2005.; Kirchwey, Freda.; Knopf, Blanche Wolf.; Kohn, Hans.; Kollek, Teddy, 1911-2007.; Krock, Arthur, 1886-1974.; Kronenberger, Louis, 1904-1980.; Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-1970.; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948.; Lash, Joseph P., 1909-1987.; Laski, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989.; Lazarsfeld, Paul Felix.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lemnitzer, Lyman L. (Lyman Louis), 1899-1988.; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992.; Levin, Meyer, 1905-1981.; Lewisohn, Sam A., 1884-1951.; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981.; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Litvinov, Ivy.; Lockwood, Lee.; Loveman, Amy.; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.; Lynes, Russell, 1910-1991.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-1980.; McWilliams, Carey, 1905-1980.; Mannes, Marya.; Matthiessen, F. O. (Francis Otto), 1902-1950.; Maverick, Maury, 1895-1954.; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978.; Michener, James A. (James Albert), 1907-1997.; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005.; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974.; Mosely, Philip E. (Philip Edward), 1905-1972.; Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1903-1990.; Murrow, Edward R.; Muste, Abraham John, 1885-1967.; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983.; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971.; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971.; Nijinska, Bronislava, 1891-1972.; O'Brien, Conor Cruise, 1917-2008.; O'Dwyer, William, 1890-1964.; O'Hara, John, 1905-1970.; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967.; Perry, Ralph Barton, 1876-1957.; Pope, Arthur Upham, 1881-1969.; Pound, Omar S.; Rama Rau, Santha, 1923-2009.; Reid, Helen Miles Rogers, 1882-; Reid, Whitelaw, 1913-; Reston, James, 1909-1995.; Reynaud, Paul, 1878-1966.; Rickover, Hyman George.; Riesman, David, 1909-2002.; Robinson, Geroid Tanquary, 1892-1971.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Roditi, Edouard.; Rogers, Lindsay, 1891-1970.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Root, Waverley, 1903-1982.; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980.; Salisbury, Harrison E. (Harrison Evans), 1908-1993.; Salk, Jonas, 1914-1995.; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967.; Schlesinger, Arthur Meyer, 1917-; Seaver, Edwin, 1900-; Sevareid, Eric, 1912-1992.; Sheean, Vincent, 1899-1975.; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955.; Shirer, William L. (William Lawrence), 1904-1993.; Simonov, Konstantin Mikhaĭlovich, 1915-1979.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; Snow, Edgar, 1905-1972.; Sokolsky, George Ephraim, 1893-1962.; Spewack, Samuel, 1899-1971.; Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1879-1962.; Stern, Isaac, 1920-2001.; Stern, Philip Van Doren, 1900-1984.; Stettinius, Edward R. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949.; Strachey, John, 1901-1963.; Straight, Michael Whitney.; Strong, Anna Louise, 1885-1970.; Swing, Raymond, 1887-1968.; Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958.; Szilard, Leo.; Taylor, Telford.; Tesla, Nikola, 1856-1943.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Thompson, Dorothy, 1893-1961.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.; Thurber, James, 1894-1961.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Uris, Leon, 1924-2003.; Van Doren, Irita Bradford, 1891-1966.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006.; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965.; Welles, Orson, 1915-1985.; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961.; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983.; White, Theodore H. (Theodore Harold), 1915-1986.; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Wilson, Harold, 1916-1995.; Winter, Ella.; Woodward, C. Vann (Comer Vann), 1908-1999.; Wyzanski, Charles Edward, 1906-; Zimbalist, Efrem, 1923-; International broadcasting.; Journalism.; World War, 1939-1945.; Addresses.; Interviews.; Authors, French.; Authors, Russian.; Foreign correspondents.; Journalists.; Lecturers.; Public officers.; Sovietologists.; Translators.; War correspondents.; New York herald tribune.
Acquisition
09/23/92 M-92-09-23 Papers Barnes, Mrs Joseph Gift
Gift of Mrs Joseph Barnes, 1992.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Adamic, Louis (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Arendt, Hannah (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish (Box 1)
  - Aydelotte, Frank (Box 1)
  - Baker, Newton D. (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash (Box 1)
  - Barr, Stringfellow (Box 1)
  - Beard, Charles A (Box 1)
  - Beebe, Lucius (Box 1)
  - Benton, Wollam (Box 1)
  - Berle, AA. (Box 1)
  - Berlin, Sir Isaiah (Box 1)
  - Blivin, Bruce (Box 1)
  - Bohlen, Charles E. (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Claude G. (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Chester (Box 1)
  - Brandt, Willy (Box 1)
  - Brown, John Mason (Box 1)
  - Bullitt, Wllllam C. (Box 1)
  - Bush, Vannevar (Box 1)
  - Catledge, Turner (Box 1)
  - Cerf, Bennett A (Box 1)
  - Chou, En-lai (Box 1)
  - Churchill, Randolph S. (Box 1)
  - Cockburn, Claud (Box 1)
  - Commager, Henry Steele (Box 1)
  - Comstock, Ada Louise (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Lady Diana (Box 1)
  - Corwin, Norman (Box 1)
  - Cowan, Louis (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 1)
  - Crichton, Kyle S. (Box 1)
  - Crossman, Richard (Box 1)
  - Curti, Merle (Box 1)
  - Davenport, Marcia (Box 1)
  - Davidson, Jo (Box 1)
  - Davies, Joseph E. (Box 1)
  - Dayan, Moshe (Box 1)
  - De Voto, Bernard (Box 1)
  - Donovan, William I. (Box 1)
  - Doolittle, James H. (Box 1)
  - Douglas, William O. (Box 1)
  - Driberg, Tom (Box 1)
  - Dulles, John Foster (Box 1)
  - Duranty, Walter (Box 1)
  - Edel, Leon (Box 1)
  - Edman, Irwin (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower, Milton S. (Box 1)
  - Ernst, Lorris L. (Box 1)
  - Evans, Ernestine (Box 1)
  - Fadiman, Clifton (Box 2)
  - Farago, Ladislas (Box 2)
  - Feis, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Field, Marshall (Box 2)
  - Flexner, Abraham (Box 2)
  - Fortas, Abe (Box 2)
  - Frankfurter, Felix (Box 2)
  - Fromm, Erich (Box 2)
  - Fry, Varian (Box 2)
  - Fulbright, James W. (Box 2)
  - Galantiere, Lewis (Box 2)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 2)
  - Gannett, Lewis (Box 2)
  - Gary, Romain (Box 2)
  - Gellhorn, Martha (Box 2)
  - Gluck. Alma (Box 2)
  - Greenslet, Fenis (Box 2)
  - Gruenther, Alfred M. (Box 2)
  - Guerard, Albert L. (Box 2)
  - Gunther, John (Box 2)
  - Halsman, Philippe (Box 2)
  - Harriman. William A. (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram (Box 2)
  - Hellman, Lillian (Box 2)
  - Hersey, John (Box 2)
  - Herter, Christian (Box 2)
  - Hindus, Maurice (Box 2)
  - Home, Lena (Box 2)
  - Houseman, John (Box 2)
  - Howe, Quincy (Box 2)
  - Huebsch, Benjamin W. (Box 2)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Box 2)
  - Ingersoll, Ralph M. (Box 2)
  - Javits, Jacob K. (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Alvin S. (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Nunnally (Box 2)
  - Josephson, Matthew (Box 2)
  - Kellogg, Paul U. (Box 3)
  - Kempton, Murray (Box 3)
  - Kennan, George F. (Box 3)
  - Kirchwey, Freda (Box 3)
  - Knopf, Blanche W. (Box 3)
  - Kohn, Hans (Box 3)
  - Kollek, Theodore (Box 3)
  - Krock, Arthur (Box 3)
  - Kronenberger, Louts (Box 3)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood (Box 3)
  - Lamont, Corliss (Box 3)
  - Lamont, Thomas W. (Box 3)
  - Lash, Joseph P. (Box 3)
  - Laski, Harold i. (Box 3)
  - Lattimore, Owen (Box 3)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul Felix (Box 3)
  - Lehman, Herbert H. (Box 3)
  - Lemnitzer, Lyman L. (Box 3)
  - Lerner, Max (Box 3)
  - Levin, Meyer (Box 3)
  - Lewisohn, Sam (Box 3)
  - Lilienthal, David E. (Box 3)
  - Lippmann, Walter (Box 3)
  - Litvinov, Ivy L. (Box 3)
  - Lockwood, Lee (Box 3)
  - Loveman, Amy (Box 3)
  - Luce, Henry (Box 3)
  - Lynes, Russell (Box 3)
  - Macleish, Archibald (Box 3)
  - McLuhan, Marshall (Box 3)
  - McWilliams, Carey (Box 3)
  - Mannes, Marya (Box 3)
  - Matthlessen, F.O. (Box 3)
  - Maverick, Maury (Box 3)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 3)
  - Miller, Arthur (Box 3)
  - Morse, Wayne (Box 3)
  - Mosely, Phillp E. (Box 3)
  - Muggertdge, Malcolm (Box 3)
  - Murrow, Edward R (Box 3)
  - Muste, A.I. (Box 3)
  - Nearing, Scott (Box 3)
  - Neibuhr, Reinhold (Box 3)
  - Nevins, Allan (Box 3)
  - Niiinska. Bronislava (Box 3)
  - O'Brien, Conor Cruise (Box 4)
  - O'Dwyer, William (Box 4)
  - O'Hara. John (Box 4)
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert (Box 4)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton (Box 4)
  - Pope, Arthur Upham (Box 4)
  - Pound, Omar S. (Box 4)
  - Rama Rau, Santha (Box 4)
  - Reid, Helen Rogers (Box 4)
  - Reid, Whitelaw (Box 4)
  - Reston, James B. (Box 4)
  - Reynaud, Paul (Box 4)
  - Rickover, Hyman G. (Box 4)
  - Riesman. David (Box 4)
  - Robinson. Geroid T. (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Box 4)
  - Roditi, Edouard (Box 4)
  - Rogers, Lindsay (Box 4)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 4)
  - Root, Waverley (Box 4)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 4)
  - Salisbury, Harrison (Box 4)
  - Salk, Jonas (Box 4)
  - Sandburg, Carl (Box 4)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Box 4)
  - Seaver, Edwin (Box 4)
  - Sevareld, Eric (Box 4)
  - Sheean, Vincent (Box 4)
  - Shenwood, Robert E. (Box 4)
  - Shirer, William L. (Box 4)
  - Simonov, Konstantine (Box 5)
  - Sinclair, Upton (Box 5)
  - Snow, Edgar (Box 5)
  - Sokolsky, George E. (Box 5)
  - Spewack, Samuel (Box 5)
  - Stefanson, Vilhjalmur (Box 5)
  - Stern, Isaac (Box 5)
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren (Box 5)
  - Stettlnius, Edward R (Box 5)
  - Strachey, John (Box 5)
  - Straight. Michael (Box 5)
  - Strong. Anna Louise (Box 5)
  - Swing. Raymond (Box 5)
  - Swope. Herbert Bayard (Box 5)
  - Szilard. Leo (Box 5)
  - Taylor. Telford (Box 5)
  - Thomas. Norman Thompson. Dorothy (Box 5)
  - Thomson. Virgil (Box 5)
  - Thurber. James (Box 5)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Box 5)
  - Untermeyer. Louis (Box 5)
  - Uris. Leon (Box 5)
  - Van Doren, Irita (Box 5)
  - Van Doren, Mark (Box 5)
  - Viereck, Peter (Box 5)
  - Wallace, Henry A. (Box 5)
  - Welles. Orson (Box 5)
  - Welles. Sumner (Box 5)
  - West-Rebecca White, Theodore H. (Box 5)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box 5)
  - Willkie, Wendell (Box 5)
  - Wilson. Harold Winter. Ella (Box 5)
  - Woodward, C. Vann (Box 5)
  - Wyzansld, Charles E., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Zimballst. Efrem. Jr. (Box 5)
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts by:
  - Bowers, Claude (Box 5)
  - Churchill, Randolph Cockburn (Box 5)
  - Claud, Gary Romain (Box 5)
  - Michener, iames (Box 5)
  - Reynaud, Paul (Box 5)
  - Sherwood. Robert (Box 5)
  - Shirer, William L. (Box 5)
  - Simonov, Konstantine (Box 5)
  - Snow, Edgar (Box 5)
  - Szilard. Leo (Box 5)
  - Taylor, Telford (Box 5)
  - Tesla, Nikola (Box 5)
- Series III: Uncataloged Papers
  - 1923-1932 (Box 6)
    - 1923 Printed (Box 6)
    - 1928 Russia (Box 6)
    - 1928 Russia Printed (Box 6)
    - 1929 Manuscript notes (Box 6)
    - 1930 Correspondence (Box 6)
    - 1930 Printed (Box 6)
    - 1931 Correspondence (Box 6)
    - 1931 Correspondence With his famtly (Box 6)
    - 1931 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 6)
    - 1931 Printed (Box 6)
    - 1932 Correspondence (Box 6)
    - 1932 Manuscritpts. etc. (Box 6)
    - 1932 Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 6)
    - 1932 Printed
      - University of London. Study for Ph.D., 1927-1930 (Box 6)
      - Freelance Journalism while visiting Russia. 1928 (Box 6)
      - Equitable Trust Co. (New York). Credit Department. 1928-1930 (Box 6)
      - Married to Kathleen Middleton. 1928-1935 (Box 6)
      - New York Herald Tribune. Stringer. 1931 (Box 6)
      - Institute of Pacific Relations. 1931-1934 (Box 6)
  - 1933 -1935 (Box 7)
    - 1933 Correspondence (Box 7)
    - 1933 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 7)
    - 1933 institute of Pacific Relatlons (Box 7)
    - 1933 Printed (Box 7)
    - 1934 Correspondence (Box 7)
    - 1934 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 7)
    - 1934 Instltute of Pacific Relations (Box 7)
    - 1934 Printed (Box 7)
    - 1934-1935 Notes (Box 7)
    - 1934-1935 Proposed new magazine for Henry Luce (Box 7)
    - 1935 Correspondence
      - Editor: Empire in the East (New York, Doubleday. 1934) (Box 7)
      - Time Inc, 1934-19S15. (Box 7)
      - New York Herald Tribune. City repoorter. 1935-1938 (Box 7)
      - American Newspaper Guild 1935-1938 (Box 7)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 8)
    - 1935 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 8)
    - 1935 Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 8)
    - 1935 Piinted (Box 8)
    - 1936 Correspondence (Box 8)
    - 1936 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 8)
    - 1936 Communist Party-USA Convention (Box 8)
    - 1936 Harvard University Tercentenary (Box 8)
    - 1936 Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 8)
    - 1936 Printed:
      - Married Elizabeth Brown field, 1938 (Box 8)
  - 1937 -1939 (Box 9)
    - 1937 Correspondence (Box 9)
    - 1937 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 9)
    - 1937 Printed (Box 9)
    - 1937-1938 Elizabeth G.B.Barnes (Box 9)
    - 1938 Correspondence (Box 9)
    - 1938 Manuscripts, etc. (Box 9)
    - 1938 Printed (Box 9)
    - 1939 Correspondence (Box 9)
    - 1939 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 9)
    - 1939 Printed
      - New York Herald Tribune, Moscow correspondent. 1937-1939 (Box 9)
      - New York Herald Tribune, Head of Berlin Bureau,. 1939 (Box 9)
      - New York Herald Tribune, Foreign News Editor. 1939-1941 (Box 9)
  - 1940 -1941 (Box 10)
    - 1940 Correspondence (Box 10)
    - 1940 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 10)
    - 1940 Office of War Information (Box 10)
    - 1940 Printed 1940-1941 Ambassador Dodd's Diary (Box 10)
    - 1941 Correspondence (Box 10)
    - 1941 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 10)
    - 1941 American Committee for international Studies (Box 10)
    - 1941 Office of War Information (Box 10)
    - 1941 Printed
      - Editor. Ambassador Dodd’s Diary (New York. Harcourt. Brace & Co. UMO). Office of War Information. Operational Bead, 1941-1944. (Box 10)
  - 1942 (Box 11)
    - 1942 Correspondence (Box 11)
    - 1942 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 11)
    - 1942 Office of War Information. correspondence (Box 11)
    - 1942 Office of War Information, manuscripts & printed (Box 11)
    - 1942 Wendell Willkie Tour, correspondence (Box 11)
    - 1942 Wendell Willkie Tour, notebook (Box 11)
    - 1942 Printed
      - Office of War Information. World Tour of Wendell Willkie. 1942 (Box 11)
  - 1943 (Box 12)
    - 1943 Correspondence (Box 12)
    - 1943 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 12)
    - 1943 Office of War information, correspondence (Box 12)
    - 1943 Office of War information, manuscripts. etc. (Box 12)
    - 1943 Office of War information, printed (Box 12)
    - 1943 Printed
      - Editor: One World by Wendell Willkie, 1943 (Box 12)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 13)
    - 1944 Correspondence (Box 13)
    - 1944 Manusripts, etc. (Box 13)
    - 1944 Office of War information, correspondence (Box 13)
    - 1944 Office of War infonnatlon, manuscripts, etc. (Box 13)
    - 1944 Office of War information, printed (Box 13)
    - 1944 Printed (Box 13)
    - 1945 Correspondence
      - New York Herald Tribune, Foreign correspondent in London, 1944 (Box 13)
      - New York Herald Tribune, Foreign Editor. 1944-1948 (Box 13)
      - Translator: Days and Nights by Konstantin Simonov, 1948 (Box 13)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 14)
    - 1945 Manuscripts, etc. (Box 14)
    - 1945 Printed (Box 14)
    - 1946 Correspondence (Box 14)
    - 1946 Manuscripts, etc. (Box 14)
    - 1946 Printed (Box 14)
  - 1947 -1948 (Box 15)
    - 1947 Correspondence (Box 15)
    - 1947 Manuscripts, etc. (Box 15)
    - 1941 McCarthy Era (Box 15)
    - 1947 Simon and Schuster. Publishers (Box 15)
    - 1947 Printed (Box 15)
    - 1948 Correspondence
      - New York Star, Editor, 1948-1949 (Box 15)
      - British Broadcasting Corp., American Commentary. 1948-1960 (Box 15)
  - 1948 (Box 16)
    - 1948 Manuscripts, etc. (Box 16)
    - 1948 McCarthy Era (Box 16)
    - 1948 New York Star/PM. correspondence (Box 16)
    - 1948 New York Star/PM. manuscripts & printed (Box 16)
    - 1948 Simon and Schuster. Publishers, correspondence (Box 16)
    - 1948 Printed (Box 16)
  - 1949-1951 (Box 17)
    - 1949 Correspondence (Box 17)
    - 1949 Manuscripts. etc. (Box 17)
    - 1949 McCarthy Era (Box 17)
    - 1949 New York Star/PM, correspondence (Box 17)
    - 1949 Simon and Schuster. Publishers. correspondence (Box 17)
    - 1949 Printed (Box 17)
    - 1950 McCarthy Era (Box 17)
    - 1950 McCarthy Era, L.Budenz (Box 17)
    - 1950 McCarthy Era. Owen Lattimore (Box 17)
    - 1951 McCarthy Era (Box 17)
    - 1951 McCarthy Era. A.G. Bannlne (Box 17)
    - 1951 McCarthy Era, E.T. Bentley (Box 17)
    - 1951 McCarthy Era. L.Budenz
      - Editor: Roosevelt and the Russians by Edward Stettinias. 1949 (Box 17)
      - Translator: The Company of Men by Romain Gary. 1950 (Box 17)
      - Editor: Modern Arms and Free Men by Vannevar Bush. 1950 (Box 17)
      - Translator: Unite or Perish by Paul Reynaud. 1950 (Box 17)
      - Sara Lawrence College, Instructor in Communications, 1950-51 (Box 17)
      - Simon and Schuster Co.. Editor. 1951 (Box 17)
  - 1951-1954 (Box 18)
  - 1951 McCarthy Era. Whittaker Chambers (Box 18)
  - 1951 McCarthy Era. Owen Lattimore (Box 18)
  - 1951 McCarthy Era. McCarran Committee (Box 18)
  - 1951 McCarthy Era. Hedy Massing (Box 18)
  - 1951 McCarthy Era, K.A. Wittfogel (Box 18)
  - 1952 McCarthy Era (Box 18)
  - 1952 McCarthy Era (Box 18)
  - Lloyd Garrison & Joseph S. Iseman 1952 McCarthy Era. Owen Lattimore 1952 McCarthy Era. McCarran Committee 1952 McCarthy Era. Sarah Lawrence College 1953 McCarthy Era 1954 McCarthy Era. (Box 18)
  - Series: Simon and Schuster Editorial Files, 1950-1970 (Box 18)
  - A -BA: (Box 19)
  - A (Box 19)
  - Abels. Cyrilly (Box 19)
  - American Culture Series (Box 19)
  - Area Studies (Box 19)
  - Asad. Muhammad (Box 19)
  - Attwood. William (Box 19)
  - The Authors Guild. inc. (Box 19)
  - B (Box 19)
  - The Balfour Declaration by Leonard J. Stein (Box 19)
  - Barnard, Ellsworth (Box 19)
  - Barnes, Joseph (Box 19)
  - BE-BUR: (Box 20)
  - Bentson, Saul (Box 20)
  - Berlin, Sir Isaiah (Box 20)
  - Bessie, Mr. & Mrs Simon Michael (Box 20)
  - Bete, Channing L. (Box 20)
  - Bevan, Aneurin & Jennie Lee (Box 20)
  - Bigart, Homer (Box 20)
  - Blochman, Lawrence G. (Box 20)
  - Book reviews & articles by Barnes (Box 20)
  - Bowden, G.T. (Box 20)
  - Bowers, Claude Gernade (Box 20)
  - Burma Translation Society (Rangoon) (Box 20)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley (Box 20)
  - BUS-CUN: (Box 21)
  - Bush. Vannevar (Box 21)
  - C (Box 21)
  - Carter, Edward C. (Box 21)
  - Civil liberties (Box 21)
  - Clark. Blair (Box 21)
  - Cockburn. Claud (Box 21)
  - Columbia University (Box 21)
  - The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science (Box 21)
  - Council on Foreign Relations. inc. (Box 21)
  - Cowan. LouiS G. (Box 21)
  - Crane. John O. (Box 21)
  - Christman, Henry M. (Box 21)
  - Cunard. Nancy (Box 21)
  - Curtis. C.P. (Box 22)
  - Curtis. Charles Pelham (Box 22)
  - D (Box 23)
  - Dartmouth College (Box 23)
  - Davies. Joseph Edward (Box 23)
  - Dedyer. Vladimlr & Vera (Box 23)
  - Dekel, Ephraim (Box 23)
  - Doubleday & Company, inc. (Box 23)
  - E (Box 24)
  - East. P.D. (Box 24)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 24)
  - Eisenhower. Dwight D. (Box 24)
  - Engler. Robert (Box 24)
  - Evans, Ernestine (Box 24)
  - Evans, Jean (Box 24)
  - F (Box 25)
  - Field, Marshall. III (Box 25)
  - Fies, Barthold (Box 25)
  - Literary Agent (Box 25)
  - Flexner. Abraham (Box 25)
  - Frank, Gerold (Box 25)
  - Frank, M.Z. (Box 25)
  - Freidin, Seymour (Box 25)
  - The Fund for the Republic. inc. (Box 25)
  - G (Box 26)
  - Gallant. Barney (Box 26)
  - Gallup. George (Box 26)
  - Gary, Romain (Box 26)
  - Gill. Joan (Box 26)
  - Ginzberg Ell (Box 26)
  - Greenleaf Robert (Box 26)